<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>The groans of the plantations, or, A true account of their grievous and extreme sufferings by the heavy impositions upon sugar and other hardships relating more particularly to the island of Barbados.</title>
            <author>Littleton, Edward, b. 1626.</author>
         </titleStmt>
         <editionStmt>
            <edition>
               <date>1689</date>
            </edition>
         </editionStmt>
         <extent>Approx. 80 KB of XML-encoded text transcribed from 19 1-bit group-IV TIFF page images.</extent>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>Text Creation Partnership,</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Ann Arbor, MI ; Oxford (UK) :</pubPlace>
            <date when="2011-04">2011-04 (EEBO-TCP Phase 2).</date>
            <idno type="DLPS">A48741</idno>
            <idno type="STC">Wing L2577</idno>
            <idno type="STC">ESTC R36481</idno>
            <idno type="EEBO-CITATION">15701080</idno>
            <idno type="OCLC">ocm 15701080</idno>
            <idno type="VID">104458</idno>
            <availability>
               <p>To the extent possible under law, the Text Creation Partnership has waived all copyright and related or neighboring rights to this keyboarded and encoded edition of the work described above, according to the terms of the CC0 1.0 Public Domain Dedication (http://creativecommons.org/publicdomain/zero/1.0/). This waiver does not extend to any page images or other supplementary files associated with this work, which may be protected by copyright or other license restrictions. Please go to https://www.textcreationpartnership.org/ for more information about the project.</p>
            </availability>
         </publicationStmt>
         <seriesStmt>
            <title>Early English books online.</title>
         </seriesStmt>
         <notesStmt>
            <note>(EEBO-TCP ; phase 2, no. A48741)</note>
            <note>Transcribed from: (Early English Books Online ; image set 104458)</note>
            <note>Images scanned from microfilm: (Early English books, 1641-1700 ; 1152:50)</note>
         </notesStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <biblFull>
               <titleStmt>
                  <title>The groans of the plantations, or, A true account of their grievous and extreme sufferings by the heavy impositions upon sugar and other hardships relating more particularly to the island of Barbados.</title>
                  <author>Littleton, Edward, b. 1626.</author>
               </titleStmt>
               <extent>[2], 35 p.   </extent>
               <publicationStmt>
                  <publisher>Printed by M. Clark ...,</publisher>
                  <pubPlace>London :</pubPlace>
                  <date>MDCLXXXIX [1689]</date>
               </publicationStmt>
               <notesStmt>
                  <note>Reproduction of original in Huntington Library.</note>
               </notesStmt>
            </biblFull>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <encodingDesc>
         <projectDesc>
            <p>Created by converting TCP files to TEI P5 using tcp2tei.xsl,
      TEI @ Oxford.
      </p>
         </projectDesc>
         <editorialDecl>
            <p>EEBO-TCP is a partnership between the Universities of Michigan and Oxford and the publisher ProQuest to create accurately transcribed and encoded texts based on the image sets published by ProQuest via their Early English Books Online (EEBO) database (http://eebo.chadwyck.com). The general aim of EEBO-TCP is to encode one copy (usually the first edition) of every monographic English-language title published between 1473 and 1700 available in EEBO.</p>
            <p>EEBO-TCP aimed to produce large quantities of textual data within the usual project restraints of time and funding, and therefore chose to create diplomatic transcriptions (as opposed to critical editions) with light-touch, mainly structural encoding based on the Text Encoding Initiative (http://www.tei-c.org).</p>
            <p>The EEBO-TCP project was divided into two phases. The 25,368 texts created during Phase 1 of the project (2000-2009), initially available only to institutions that contributed to their creation, were released into the public domain on 1 January 2015. The approximately 40,000 texts produced during Phase 2 (2009- ), of which 34,963 had been released as of 2020, originally similarly restricted, were similarly freed from all restrictions on 1 August 2020. As of that date anyone is free to take and use these texts for any purpose (modify them, annotate them, distribute them, etc.). But we do respectfully request that due credit and attribution be given to their original source.</p>
            <p>Users should be aware of the process of creating the TCP texts, and therefore of any assumptions that can be made about the data.</p>
            <p>Text selection was based on the New Cambridge Bibliography of English Literature (NCBEL). If an author (or for an anonymous work, the title) appears in NCBEL, then their works are eligible for inclusion. Selection was intended to range over a wide variety of subject areas, to reflect the true nature of the print record of the period. In general, first editions of a works in English were prioritized, although there are a number of works in other languages, notably Latin and Welsh, included and sometimes a second or later edition of a work was chosen if there was a compelling reason to do so.</p>
            <p>Image sets were sent to external keying companies for transcription and basic encoding. Quality assurance was then carried out by editorial teams in Oxford and Michigan. 5% (or 5 pages, whichever is the greater) of each text was proofread for accuracy and those which did not meet QA standards were returned to the keyers to be redone. After proofreading, the encoding was enhanced and/or corrected and characters marked as illegible were corrected where possible up to a limit of 100 instances per text. Any remaining illegibles were encoded as &lt;gap&gt;s. Understanding these processes should make clear that, while the overall quality of TCP data is very good, some errors will remain and some readable characters will be marked as illegible. Users should bear in mind that in all likelihood such instances will never have been looked at by a TCP editor.</p>
            <p>The texts were encoded and linked to page images in accordance with level 4 of the TEI in Libraries guidelines.</p>
            <p>Copies of the texts have been issued variously as SGML (TCP schema; ASCII text with mnemonic sdata character entities); displayable XML (TCP schema; characters represented either as UTF-8 Unicode or text strings within braces); or lossless XML (TEI P5, characters represented either as UTF-8 Unicode or TEI g elements).</p>
            <p>Keying and markup guidelines are available at the <ref target="http://www.textcreationpartnership.org/docs/.">Text Creation Partnership web site</ref>.</p>
         </editorialDecl>
         <listPrefixDef>
            <prefixDef ident="tcp"
                       matchPattern="([0-9\-]+):([0-9IVX]+)"
                       replacementPattern="http://eebo.chadwyck.com/downloadtiff?vid=$1&amp;page=$2"/>
            <prefixDef ident="char"
                       matchPattern="(.+)"
                       replacementPattern="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/textcreationpartnership/Texts/master/tcpchars.xml#$1"/>
         </listPrefixDef>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="eng">eng</language>
         </langUsage>
         <textClass>
            <keywords scheme="http://authorities.loc.gov/">
               <term>Tariff --  Great Britain.</term>
               <term>Sugar trade --  Great Britain.</term>
               <term>Sugar --  Manufacture and refining --  Barbados.</term>
            </keywords>
         </textClass>
      </profileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change>
            <date>2009-11</date>
            <label>TCP</label>Assigned for keying and markup</change>
         <change>
            <date>2009-12</date>
            <label>SPi Global</label>Keyed and coded from ProQuest page images</change>
         <change>
            <date>2010-01</date>
            <label>Pip Willcox</label>Sampled and proofread</change>
         <change>
            <date>2010-01</date>
            <label>Pip Willcox</label>Text and markup reviewed and edited</change>
         <change>
            <date>2010-04</date>
            <label>pfs</label>Batch review (QC) and XML conversion</change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text xml:lang="eng">
      <front>
         <div type="title_page">
            <pb facs="tcp:104458:1"/>
            <pb facs="tcp:104458:1"/>
            <p>THE GROANS of the PLANTATIONS: OR A True ACCOUNT OF THEIR <hi>Grievous and Extreme Sufferings</hi> By the Heavy IMPOSITIONS UPON SUGAR, And other HARDSHIPS.</p>
            <p>Relating more particularly to the ISLAND of <hi>BARBADOS.</hi>
            </p>
            <p>
               <hi>LONDON,</hi> Printed by <hi>M. Clark</hi> in the Year MDCLXXXIX.</p>
         </div>
      </front>
      <body>
         <div type="complaint">
            <pb facs="tcp:104458:2"/>
            <pb n="1" facs="tcp:104458:2"/>
            <head>The GROANS of the PLANTATIONS.</head>
            <p>
               <hi>YO<g ref="char:V">Ʋ</g> have here the Caſe of the Plantations preſented to-your view: which you will find to be moſt lamentable. You will find, that as the Old Duties upon Sugar did</hi> fleece us, <hi>ſo the Addition of the New doth</hi> flea us. <hi>And you will likewiſe perceive, that when we treat of theſe Matters, our Minds are ſometimes under great diſturbances. There are ſome things that make even wiſe Men mad. and therefore We, who do not pretend to that high attainment, muſt not be wondered at; if in the Anguiſh of our Souls we let fall ſome Expreſſions, that ſeem little better than</hi> Ravings. <hi>However we thought it concern'd us to lay open our Condition in any manner. that ſo the World may know, by what cruel Methods, and by what fatal De<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>grees, the once flouriſhing Engliſh Colonies have been brought to ruine. But our chief end is to get Relief. which if it cannot be had, (as God forbid but it ſhould); it will yet be ſome Comfort in our Mi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſeries, if we obtain Compaſſion.</hi>
            </p>
            <p>
               <seg rend="decorInit">I</seg>N FORMER times we accounted our ſelves a part of <hi>England:</hi> and the Trade and Entercourſe was open accordingly. ſo that Commodities came hither as freely from the Sugar Planta<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tions, as from the Iſles of <hi>Wight</hi> or <hi>Angle<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſey.</hi>
            </p>
            <p>But upon the King's Reſtauration we were in effect made Fo<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rainers and Aliens: a Cuſtom being laid upon our Sugars amongſt other Forain Commodities. And this was in a higher Proportion than others: that is, above the common Poundage of Twelve Pence in the Pound. For eighteen pence a Hundred, was laid upon <hi>Muſcovadoes,</hi> and five Shillings upon <hi>Whites:</hi>
               <pb n="2" facs="tcp:104458:3"/>the common price of the <hi>Muſcovado</hi> Hundred being little above twenty Shillings, and the <hi>Whites</hi> under fifty.</p>
            <p>At the ſame time the Duty of four and a half <hi>per Cent.</hi> was extorted from us in <hi>Barbados,</hi> full ſore againſt our Wills. For it may well be imagined, that we had no mind to burden our own Commodities. The uſes of this Duty were pretended and expreſs'd to be; For ſupport of the Government, and for the pub<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lick Services of the Iſland. But the Duty was ſoon farmed out for Money payable in <hi>England.</hi> Which Money hath been here paid, and none of the Uſes performed, nor any thing allowed towards them. And all the Applications that we have made for it, have been without ſucceſs. So that we make and repair our Forts and Breſt works, we build our Magazines, we buy our great Guns and Ammunition; and are forced to lay great Taxes upon our ſelves, for defraying theſe and all other pub<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lick Charges. Moreover this <hi>four and a half</hi> is collected in ſuch manner, that in the Judgment of all that have tryed it, the Attendance and Slavery is a greater burden than the Duty.</p>
            <p>Upon the laying theſe Impoſitions (the one in <hi>England,</hi> the other in <hi>Barbados</hi>) the price of Sugar continued the ſame: nor could we in the leaſt advance it, either then or any time ſince. So that we find plainly, that we the poor Planters bear the whole burden of theſe Duties: and whatever we pay, year after year, by occaſion of them; is the ſame thing in effect, as a Land-Tax upon our Eſtates.</p>
            <p>LET us now conſider the proportion of this Tax: and firſt, what it comes to in <hi>Muſcovadoes.</hi> We will ſuppoſe that four pound and an half of this Sugar (which is the <hi>Barbados</hi> Duty) is there worth but fix pence. This, with the eighteen pence paid in <hi>England,</hi> makes two Shillings. Since therefore we rec<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>koned a Hundred of <hi>Muſcovado</hi> at about twenty Shillings; you will ſay the Duties lie upon the Planter, as a Land-Tax of two Shillings in the Pound.</p>
            <p>But this is not a true Reckoning. for if you will reckon right, you muſt conſider; not what is the full Value of ſuch a Hun<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dred of Sugar, but what is the clear Profit. For out of this Profit the Planter pays the Duties: that is, by the payment
<pb n="3" facs="tcp:104458:3"/>of them his clear Gains are the leſs by two Shillings in each Hundred. The ordinary clear Profit of a Hundred of <hi>Muſcova do</hi> may be about five Shillings: or hardly ſo much. for, for one Hundred that yields it, three or four fall ſhort. However, that we may a little flatter and deceive our ſelves, we will ſuppoſe this clear Profit to be fix Shillings. and then the Duties draw two Shillings out of ſix, and are as a Land-Tax of a Noble in the pound. But if the Sugar yield only two and twenty Shil<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lings, the Duty ſwallows up the whole Profit; if it yield but twenty, the Planter pays the Duty out of his Pocket, and muſt live by the loſs. and there is many a hundred of Sugar ſold under twenty.</p>
            <p>We have truly ſaid, that the ordinary Profit of a <hi>Muſcova<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>do</hi> Hundred is but five Shillings. ſince to clear ſo much, the Sugar muſt be ſold for five and twenty: which is a full price. For it ſtands the Planter in twenty ſhillings: that is, ten the making, and ten the tranſporting. That the Cask, Fraight, and other Charges of the Tranſportation, come to ten ſhillings, for every hundred that comes to <hi>England;</hi> is known to all Merchants and Factors that uſe the Trade. And it is as well known to all Planters, that whoever makes Sugar for ten ſhil<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lings a Hundred, ſhall not get a Groat a day for his <hi>Negroes</hi> labour: though he reckon nothing for his Land, nor for his great and chargeable Buildings. And theſe <hi>Negroes</hi> ſtand him in near thirty pound a Head, by that time they are ſeaſoned. So that they cannot in truth be afforded, to work at ſuch low and mi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſerable Wages.</p>
            <p>Thus we ſee that it is a great Miſtake to think, that the old Duties upon Sugar, are but as a triſling Land-Tax of two ſhillings yearly in the pound. Though even this, in <hi>England,</hi> would not be accounted a Trifle: it being more than the Tax of ſeventy thouſand pounds a Month, made perpetual. For that month<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ly Tax, take one place with another, doth not amount to more than eighteen pence in the pound for the whole year. Where<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>as our old Duties, as it hath been made out, are as a con<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſtant Land-Tax of a Noble in the pound: and ſhear from us a third part of our Eſtates.</p>
            <pb n="4" facs="tcp:104458:4"/>
            <p>IF THE Impoſitions be thus heavy upon <hi>Muſcovado</hi> Sugars, they are much worſe upon <hi>Whites:</hi> which pay more than tre<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ble the Duty, and ſeldom reach double the price. Though in reaſon, it muſt be confeſs'd, their price ſhould be treble: con<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſidering the Room and the Time they take in Curing, together with the Labour and the Waſte. But there is no diſputing: we muſt take for them what we can get.</p>
            <p>It was ſome eaſe to us for a while, that though our Sugars were ſo burden'd in <hi>England,</hi> yet they came free to our Nor<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>thern Plantations in <hi>America.</hi> But this did not long continue. For it pleaſed the Parliament of <hi>England</hi> to ſtretch forth their Hands, and to lay them upon us in thoſe remote Parts, they having made an Act, which is dutifully obeyed, That all Sugars that go to the Plantations aforeſaid, ſhall pay the ſaid Duty of eighteen pence and ſive ſhillings, at the Places from whence they are exported. So that now we have no way to avoid any part of the Burden. Which alſo is a grievous Clog to our Commerce with thoſe Plantations.</p>
            <p>The Burden of the Duties paid before Exportation is then moſt ſenſible, and ſeems to preſs hardeſt upon us, when the Goods for which we have paid them are loſt at Sea. Which ſometimes happens before our faces, if the <hi>Hurricane</hi> catch the Ships before they ſail. We therefore thought it not unrea<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſonable to expect the ſame favour, that Merchants (in the like caſe) have in <hi>England</hi> and other places, to Ship off the like Quantity Cuſtom free. And we prepared and paſs'd an Act for that purpoſe: which we alſo tranſmitted to <hi>England.</hi> hum<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>bly hoping, that we ſhould ſind no difficulty in obtaining the Royal Aſſent. But by it we incurr'd very great diſpleaſure: and our Act was not only diſallowed, whereby it became of no effect, but we were commanded expreſly to repeal it. which we did, with Hearts full of Sorrow.</p>
            <p>MOREOVER there are divers things, whereby our Con<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dition is made worſe than it was in former Times, and which make us leſs able to bear theſe Impoſitions. Of which Things I ſhall name ſome ſew.</p>
            <pb n="5" facs="tcp:104458:4"/>
            <p>Heretofore we could Ship off our Goods at any Port, or Bay, or Creek; and at any time, either by day or by night. But now ſince the Kings Reſtauration we muſt do it at thoſe Times and Places only, at which the Collectors of the Cuſtoms pleaſe to attend.</p>
            <p>Heretofore we might ſend our Commodities to any part of the World. But now we muſt ſend them to <hi>England,</hi> and to no Place elſe. By which means the whole Trade of Sugars to the <hi>Streights,</hi> (to ſay nothing of other Places), is loſt both to Us and to the <hi>Engliſh</hi> Nation. For by multiplying our Charge, others can underſell us. We hear of a certain old Law in <hi>Scotland,</hi> Markets, before they might Ship them off. And ſurely if they had ſtudied ſeven years, for a Law to deſtroy their Fiſhing Trade, they could not have found one more effectual. In the like manner it may be truly affirmed, that the bringing all Sugars to the <hi>Engliſh</hi> Market, hath gone a great way in de<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſtroying that Trade. As for confining the Plantation Trade to <hi>Engliſh</hi> Ships and <hi>Engliſh</hi> Men, though it be to our particular Loſs, (for the <hi>Dutch</hi> were very beneſicial to us); yet we took it in good part, in regard our great and dear Mother of <hi>England</hi> hath by it ſuch vaſt Advantages. But that <hi>Engliſh</hi> Ships and <hi>Engliſh</hi> Men ſhould not be permitted to trade to their beſt con<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>venience and profit, is a thing we cannot underſtand. The great End and Deſign of Trade, as to the Publick, is to get the ſo<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>reign Money: and ſuch means ſhould be uſed, as do moſt conduce to that End.</p>
            <p>Heretofore the things we wanted were brought to us from the Places where they might beſt be had. But now we muſt have them from <hi>England,</hi> and from no other Place. Had we been confined to <hi>England</hi> only, for thoſe Things that <hi>England</hi> doth produce, we ſhould have been well contented. But that we muſt fetch from <hi>England</hi> the Things that are produced elſewhere, ſeems very hard. we are ſure it makes the Prices exceſſive to us.</p>
            <p>HERETOFORE we might ſend to <hi>Guiney</hi> for <hi>Negroes</hi> when we wanted them. and they ſtood us in about ſeven pound a Head. The Account is ſhort and plain. For they coſt about
<pb n="6" facs="tcp:104458:5"/>the value of forty ſhillings a Head in <hi>Guiney;</hi> and their freight was five pound, for every one that was brought alive, and could go over the Ship ſide. But now we are ſhut out of this Trade: and a Company is put upon us, from whom we muſt have our <hi>Negroes,</hi> and no other way. A Company of <hi>London</hi> Merchants have got a Patent, excluding all others, to furniſh the Plantati<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ons with <hi>Negroes:</hi> ſome great Men being joyned with them, with whom we were not able to contend. But thoſe great Men might have had ſome better Exerciſe for their Generoſity, than the preſſing too hard upon (we muſt not ſay, oppreſſing) induſtrious People. And now we buy <hi>Negroes</hi> at the price of an Engroſs'd Commodity: the common Rate of a good <hi>Negro</hi> on Ship board being twenty pound. And we are forced to ſcram<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ble for them in ſo ſhameful a Manner, that one of the great Burdens of our Lives is the going to buy <hi>Negroes.</hi> But we muſt have them; we cannot be without them, and the beſt Men in thoſe Countries muſt in their own Perſons ſubmit to the Indignity.</p>
            <p>There never want fair Pretences for the fouleſt Monopolies. But what do they pretend for this? They will tell you, that (to the common Good and Benefit of the <hi>Engliſh</hi> Nation) they can deal with the People of <hi>Africa</hi> to much better advantage, by being a Company. And ſo they might, if they could ſhut out other Nations. But ſince the <hi>Dutch, French, Danes, Swedes,</hi> and others, trade thither, and they can ſhut out none but the poor <hi>Engliſh;</hi> their being a Company, as to their dealing with the Natives, ſignifies nothing. And it plainly appears, that 'tis not upon the People of <hi>Africa,</hi> but upon the <hi>Engliſh</hi> Planters in <hi>America,</hi> that they make their advantage. They will alſo tell you of the neceſſity of Forts and Garriſons, and that a Com<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>pany was therefore neceſſary. But theſe might have been made and maintain'd without a Company, by an Impoſition upon <hi>Negroes</hi> ſold, or ſome ſuch Tax, to which the Plantations would cheerfully have ſubmitted.</p>
            <p>It may well be imagin'd, (no, it cannot be imagin'd), how the Company and their Agents Lord it over us, having us thus in their power. And if any offer at the Trade beſide themſelves, they make ſuch Examples of them, that few dare
<pb n="7" facs="tcp:104458:5"/>follow them. If they catch us at <hi>Guiney,</hi> they uſe us down<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>right as Enemies. And at home we are drag'd into the Admi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ralty Courts, and condemned in a trice. there is not ſuch ſpee<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dy Juſtice in all the World. And the word is, that we are found Prize; or condemn'd as Prize. as if we were Forrainers, taken in open War.</p>
            <p>They have got a trick of late, to bring <hi>Interlopers</hi> within the acts of Navigation or Trade: which are the ſevere Acts about Plantations. But even in this caſe we are brought into the Ad<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>miralty, what ever the Law ſays to the contrary. Nor doth it avail us to plead, that all Offences againſt Statutes muſt be tryed by Jury.</p>
            <p>The Forfeitures of the Acts before-named (which are never leſs than Ship and Goods) are given to the King, the Gover<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nour, and the Informer. The Governour, in theſe Matters, ſits chief Judge of the Court: I am ſure <hi>Dutton</hi> did in his time. The Company's Agents, who are the Informers, (or ſome Ser<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>vant in their behalf) ſit with him. and as ſoon as Sentence is given, they divide the Spoyle. And what ever becomes of the Kings ſhare, we may be ſure the Pains takers will not loſe theirs. But the while the Kings Subjects in thoſe Parts are in a bleſſed Condition.</p>
            <p>They contemn the Laws againſt Monopolies: and they tell us, that the Laws of <hi>England</hi> are not in force among us in this Matter. though they are in all things elſe, ſave only where our own Special Laws do make ſome difference.</p>
            <p>Of all the Things we have occaſion for, <hi>Negroes</hi> are the moſt neceſſary, and the moſt valuable. And therefore to have them under a Company, and under a Monopoly, whereby their pri<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ces are more then doubled, nay almoſt trebled; cannot but be moſt grievous to us. Many an Eſtate hath been ſunk, and many a Family hath been ruin'd, by the highprices they give for <hi>Negroes.</hi> One would think, that while we were under ſuch a Company, there were little need of Impoſitions to undo us.</p>
            <p>Theſe Duties and theſe Hardſhips we have lain under, du<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ring the Reign of King <hi>Charles</hi> the Second. And we have born them as well as we could. But ſome were not able: and ſunk under the Weight. being put out of all Capacity, to pay their
<pb n="8" facs="tcp:104458:6"/>Debts, and provide for their Families. For having ſo many Preſſures beſide, they could not undergo thoſe Impoſitions, by which a third part of their Eſtates was lop't off. Where a Man had threeſcore pound a year in all the World, and found it little enough, and too little; it was too hard upon him to pay twenty pound a year out of it. Alſo if a Planter be in debt (as moſt of us are), ſo that not a fourth part of his Eſtate comes clear to him, above the Intereſt he paies; how is he able to pay a third part in Taxes?</p>
            <p>UPON the coming of King <hi>James</hi> to the Crown, a Parlia<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ment being called, We were preparing a Complaint againſt the Commiſſioners of the Cuſtoms. Who had taken a liberty of late, to our grievous prejudice, to call that <hi>White</hi> Sugar, which had never been accounted ſuch before, and which was far from that Colour. And whatever They pleaſed to call <hi>Whites,</hi> muſt pay the Duty of five ſhillings the Hundred.</p>
            <p>But we were ſoon forced to lay aſide theſe Thoughts, to pro<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>vide againſt a new Storm that threaten'd. For we were told, to our great Aſtoniſhment, that a Project was ſet on foot to lay more Load upon us: no leſs then ſeven Groats a Hun<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dred more upon <hi>Muſcovado,</hi> and ſeven ſhillings upon Sugars <hi>fit for <g ref="char:V">Ʋ</g>ſe.</hi> for that was now the word. We ſaw this tended plainly to our deſtruction. but the thing was driven on furi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ouſly by ſome <hi>Empſons</hi> and <hi>Dudleys</hi> about the late King; who did not care how many People they deſtroyed, ſo they might get Favour and Preferment for themſelves.</p>
            <p>Since we were put into the Heard of Forrainers, and paid Duties with them; we hoped we ſhould fare no worſe than other Forrainers did. But that the Plantations ſhould be ſin<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>gled out, as the hunted Deer; and the burden upon their Com<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>modities ſhould be doubled and almoſt trebled, when all others were untoucht; was matter of Amazement and Conſternation. We humbly moved, that if the whole Tax muſt be laid upon Trade, it might be laid upon all Commodities alike. We ſaid that a ſmall advance upon all the Cuſtoms, might ſerve every purpoſe, as well as a great one upon ſome. and that this might be born with ſome eaſe, there being ſo many ſhoulders to bear
<pb n="9" facs="tcp:104458:6"/>it. But they would hearken to nothing of that kind: being reſolved and fixt to lay the whole burden upon the Plantations. Which could not but ſeem very ſtrange to us.</p>
            <p>But here lay the Myſtery. The Projectors conſider'd, that if other Forrainers were hardly uſed in <hi>England,</hi> they would car<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ry or ſend their Commodities to other Places. But we poor <hi>Engliſh Forrainers</hi> are compell'd to bring all Hither. and there<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fore they thought they could hold Our Noſes to the Grind-ſtone, and make us pay what they pleaſed.</p>
            <p>However they told us, that this new Duty ſhould do us no hurt: in regard it was to be paid by the Buyer. But this we knew to be a meer Mockery. (the Mockery ſeem'd almoſt as bad as the Cruelty.) For if an Impoſt be laid upon the Sugar, who ever pays it, the Planter is ſure to bear it. VVhat avails it though the Buyer pays the Duty, if the Seller muſt preſently allow it in the price?</p>
            <p>The Brewer hath a certain price for his Beer: and he adds the Exciſe or Duty to his price: and the Cuſtomer pays it. But where the price is uncertain, and a bargain is to be driven, and a Duty yet to be paid; the firſt word of this bargain will be, who muſt pay the Duty? And 'tis not not the Appointment of Law, but the Agreement of the Parties, that muſt decide the queſtion. In Our caſe, the Buyer will naturally be at this lock: If you clear the Duty, I will give you ſo much for a Hundred of your White Sugar; if I muſt pay it, you muſt have ſeven ſhil<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lings leſs. Which is as broad as long.</p>
            <p>The Buyer, they ſay, muſt pay the Duty. but ſure the Sel<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ler may pay it if he pleaſe. And he will pleaſe to pay it, rather then not ſell his Sugar. If He will not, there are enow beſide that will.</p>
            <p>This Duty upon Sugar is the ſame thing in effect, as a Duty of twelve pence a Buſhel would be upon Corn. Though it be ſaid that the Buyer ſhall pay this, yet the Seller or the Farmer would be ſure to feel it, and it would be a heavy Tax upon the Land.</p>
            <p>Theſe plain things notwithſtanding, and what ever elſe we could ſay, the <hi>Projectors</hi> ſtood ſtoutly to it in the Parliament houſe, that the New Tax upon Sugars ſhould not burden the
<pb n="10" facs="tcp:104458:7"/>Plantations. But this was eſteemed ſuch barbarous Nonſenſe, that there was little fear of their prevailing, had not the late King (to our great unhappineſs) been ſo ſtrangely earneſt for this Tax. Which yet that Parliament, who then denied him nothing, had never granted, but that ſome Privy Councellors aſſured them, in the Kings name and as by his Order; that if the Duty pro<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ved grievous to the Plantations, it ſhould be taken off, and be no longer collected.</p>
            <p>So the Act paſſed, and the Plantations are ruin'd. For now we feel, what we certainly foreſaw, that the whole Burden of this new Duty lies upon the Plantations. No Chapman will meddle with our Sugars, unleſs we clear the Duty. Which when we have done, we are ſo far from being able to advance the price, that it is rather lower than ever it was before. 'Tis not Impoſitions, but Plenty and Scarcity that rules the Market. And it is found by conſtant Experience, That where an Impoſt is laid upon a Commodity in demand, there the Buyer may be brought to bear ſome part of it. But if the Market be glutted, and the Commodity be a Drug, (as Ours is, and for ever will be); in this caſe the Buyer will bear no part of the Duty, but the Seller muſt pay it all.</p>
            <p>IT hath been ſaid before, that the cleer Profit of a Hundred of <hi>Muſcovado</hi> Sugar, take one with another, may be about five ſhillings: or to reckon largely, about ſix. And you have ſeen that the old Duties upon that ſort are two ſhillings; and the new, two ſhillings four pence. So that the Duties do now take four ſhillings four pence out of ſix ſhillings. Which ſweeps away above two thirds of our Eſtates, and lies upon us as an effectual Land-Tax of fourteen ſhillings in the pound.</p>
            <p>To make the Computation another way; We find that what we pay yearly in Duties, is much more then the whole Rent of our Lands. And if this be true (as it is moſt true) in <hi>Barbados,</hi> where we reckon our Land at twenty ſhillings an Acre; it goes to a greater degree in the other Plantations, where Land is much cheaper. But by this means we are wholly ſtripp'd of our Lands and Freeholds, and are made worſe then Rack-Tenants. For
<pb n="11" facs="tcp:104458:7"/>we have not the whole profit of our Stocks to live upon; ſince a good part even of this, muſt go help to pay our Taxes.</p>
            <p>THE ordinary midling price of <hi>Muſcovado</hi> Sugars, hath been reckoned at ſix and twenty ſhillings a hundred at moſt. For as it hath been ſaid, many are ſold under twenty. And on the other ſide if they riſe to thirty ſhillings, they will be adjudged <hi>fit for <g ref="char:V">Ʋ</g>ſe:</hi> many under that price being ſo adjudged. In which caſe they muſt pay ſeven ſhillings a Hundred for the new Duty, beſide the old Duties which come to two ſhillings. If we do but Sun-dry our Sugar, to keep it from running away in its paſſage home; this pitiful ſtuff will be adjudged <hi>fit for <g ref="char:V">Ʋ</g>ſe,</hi> and muſt pay the ſeven ſhillings. But if the Sugars will reach five and thirty ſhillings, they are ſure to be adjudged <hi>Whites.</hi> And then they pay ſeven ſhillings for the new Duty, and five ſhillings for the old. beſide the Duty in <hi>Barbados,</hi> which in ſuch Sugar comes to neer eighteen pence. Which makes in the whole above thirteen ſhillings: and for the moſt part is more then the whole Gains of that Sugar.</p>
            <p>Whereas we talk of Sugars adjudged <hi>fit for <g ref="char:V">Ʋ</g>ſe,</hi> and others adjugded to be <hi>Whites;</hi> You will ask, where and in what Court are theſe things adjudged? I anſwer, In the Court of the High Commiſſioners. You will ſay, the Court of High Commiſſion<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ers is damned. why then, to ſpeak plainly, we mean the Com<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>miſſioners of the Cuſtoms: thoſe are Our High Commiſſioners. And 'tis They that adjudge theſe Matters, at their diſcretion.</p>
            <p>I know it doth not become us, conſidering our Condition, to jeſt at theſe Matters. But our Miſeries make us ſavage: they make us forget all Rules of Decency.</p>
            <p>All other Duties are put in certainty: and ſo might Ours too. But We only are thought fit to be left to diſcretion. But how ſhould the Duties upon Sugars be made certain? By let<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ting them be according to the value of the Sugars. And if the Officer, or any for him, had liberty to take the Sugars at ten <hi>per Cent</hi> under the price given in, no man would give an under value.</p>
            <p>IN <hi>Barbados,</hi> we can get but little by making Sugar (though it had none of theſe Burdens) except we improve it: that is,
<pb n="12" facs="tcp:104458:8"/>purge it, and give it a Colour. Others can live by making plain Sugar: We muſt live by the improved. This is all the help we have, againſt the diſadvantages we ly under: in this we are willing to take Pains, and content to take Time; and in this lies the Planters chiefeſt Skill. But the Duties fall ſo terribly upon our improved Sugars, that it doth quite diſcou<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rage and confound us. Our Ingenuity is baffled, and our In<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>duſtry cut up by the roots: here they have us, and there they have us; and we know not which way to turn our ſelves.</p>
            <p>WE can make ſhift ſometimes to put off our fine Sugar to ſome little Profit, above the Charges and the Duties. But our <hi>Courſe-Clayed</hi> (and much of our Sugar is ſuch, for all will not be fine) is quite beaten out of the Pit. We cannot ſell it in <hi>England</hi> but with ſo great Loſs, that it would turn us ſud<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>denly a begging. We are therefore forced to Ship it off for Forrain Markets: half the old Duty (I mean that in <hi>England</hi>) being allowed us back. But then new Cask muſt be bought, and new Fraight muſt be paid, and there are all the Charges of unſhipping it and ſhipping it again, and the half Duty ſtill lyes upon us. So that we are upon very unequal terms with thoſe Sellers of other Nations, who are ſuffer directly to thoſe Markets. Whereas we are compell'd to bring theſe Sugars firſt to <hi>England,</hi> where we cannot ſell them. which makes our Condition moſt lamentable. Moreover the Forrain Markets are glutted as well as Ours: and there alſo we meet with new Duties and Impoſitions. For other People have learn'd by the Example of <hi>England,</hi> to load us without Mercy. Up<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>on the whole Matter; the Sugars we thus Ship off, do turn for the moſt part to a poor and miſerable account.</p>
            <p>THE <hi>Projectors</hi> did pride themſelves in the drawing of the New Act: as a thing of great Art and Skill. whereas of all that ever were drawn, it is the moſt fooliſh. This is not ſpoken, to reflect upon the Wiſdom of the Parliament that paſt the Act, but upon the Projectors Folly that drew it. Their Folly lies in this, that they make ſo much ado about nothing. So ma<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ny confounded turnings and windings, Bonds to be given and
<pb n="13" facs="tcp:104458:8"/>taken up again, other things to be done and undone; and all to make an appearance of obliging the Buyer to pay the Duty, which is not effected in any meaſure, nor ever can be. But in the mean while, all theſe things lick Money from the Planter. For the Officers will have their Fees for every thing they do. And if any thing ſhould be ordered to be done without Fee, it would never be done. Alſo by this means the Facture is made ſo uneaſy, ſo troubleſome, ſo vexatious and ſlaviſh; that none care to meddle with our Commiſſions. Heretofore our Commiſſions were courted: but now they go a begging. One good thing there is in the <hi>Projectors</hi> Contrivances, that by means of them we have ſome Time for payment of the Duties. But if they had given us the Time, and kept all the reſt to themſelves, leaving us to pay the Duty directly and the plain way, without ſo much as naming their Conſumptioner; they had done us a Courteſy.</p>
            <p>THESE heavy Duties have been exacted from us, not only with extremity of Rigour, but alſo with manifeſt Injuſtice and Oppreſſion. As we can particularly make it out, when ever we are called to it.</p>
            <p>We have been in the hands of Men without Mercy: who de<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lighted in the Calamities of the People; and who would wil<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lingly have ſeen the whole Kingdom of <hi>England,</hi> in the ſame mi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſerable Condition that the Plantations are in. Our Sufferings were but a Prelude to the <hi>French</hi> Government: Or, as a lead<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing Card. Of which Government it is an eſſential part, that People in general pay all they are worth in Taxes.</p>
            <p>We made our humble Applications ſeveral times to the late King, and laid our Diſtreſſes before him. But he was not pleaſed to take off our Burdens or any part of them, nor to give us the leaſt Eaſe or Mitigation. One time we were referr'd to the Commiſſioners of the Cuſtoms: amongſt whom (to our com<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fort) we might find our Friends the Projectors. Another time we were told by a Great Miniſter of State (who was a princi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>pal Projector likewiſe, and who was to give us our Anſwer) <hi>That it was very undecent, not to ſay undutiful, to tax the King with his Promiſe.</hi> When as we had only ſaid in our ſubmiſſive Pe<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tition,
<pb n="14" facs="tcp:104458:9"/>That we had been encouraged to Addreſs to his Majeſty, by the gracious Expreſſions he had been pleaſed to uſe in Par<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>liament, concerning his Plantations.</p>
            <p>WE cannot now be at the Charge to procure and keep White Servants, or to entertain Freemen as we uſed to do. Nor will they now go upon any terms to a Land of Miſery and Beg<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>gery. So that our <hi>Militia</hi> muſt fall: and we ſhall be in no Capacity to defend our ſelves, either againſt a Forrain Enemy, or againſt our own <hi>Negroes.</hi>
            </p>
            <p>In the mean time our poor Slaves bear us Company in our Mones, and groan under the burden of theſe heavy Impoſiti<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ons. They know that by reaſon of them, They muſt fare and work the harder. And that their Maſters cannot now allow them, and provide for them, as they ſhould and would.</p>
            <p>IT is no wonder if Planters break (as now they do every day) ſince they ly under ſuch heavy Burdens. We ſend our Bills to <hi>England,</hi> deſigning they ſhould be paid out of the produce of the Sugars we ſend with them. But the clear Profit of our Su<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>gars being ſwallowed up by the Impoſitions; Our Bills are not paid, but come back Proteſted; and our Debts remain and in<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>creaſe upon us. And at laſt our Eſtates are torn in pieces to pay them, and will not do it.</p>
            <p>Moſt of Us Planters are behind hand, and in debt. and ſo we were, before the Impoſitions gave us their helping hand. For there is no place in the World, where it is ſo eaſy to run into debt, and ſo hard to get out of it. But now theſe heavy Impoſi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tions do ſo diſable us, that we can by no means contend with In<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tereſt, but muſt ſink under it. Heretofore we endeavour'd to work out our Debts; but now we muſt work to pay our Taxes.</p>
            <p>MANY that had good Eſtates four years ago, are now worſe then nothing, and in a ſtarving Condition: theſe heavy Impo<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſitions having quite undone them. It were a Mercy to take away our Lives, rather then leave them to us with ſo much bitterneſs. They that have Puppies or Kitlings, more then they are willing to keep; chooſe rather to drown them, then to let them periſh miſera<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>bly for want of Suſtenance. And thoſe poor little Creatures find ſo
<pb n="15" facs="tcp:104458:9"/>much pity, that when they muſt live no longer, People take care to give them an eaſy Death. But we poor Planters cannot have that favour. It is our hard lot to live, depriv'd of the Com<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>forts and Supports of Life.</p>
            <p>What have we done, or wherein have we offended, that we ſhould be uſed in this manner? Or what ſtrange Crime have we committed, to make us the Object of ſo great Severities? And how have we incurred the diſpleaſure of <hi>England,</hi> our great and dear Mother? The very Senſe of our dear Mothers diſpleaſure (though the direful Effects had not followed), and the very Thought that we are grown hateful to her, is worſe then death it ſelf. Had we been in the hands of our Enemies, and They had ſet themſelves to cruſh and oppreſs us; it had been in ſome meaſure to be born, becauſe we could expect no better. but to be ruin'd by thoſe, by whom we hoped to be che<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>riſh't and protected, is wholly unſupportable.</p>
            <p>THESE things notwithſtanding, our Hearts continue as firm to <hi>England,</hi> as if all were well with us. Nor can any Uſage leſſen our Obſequious Devotion to our dear and native Country. We renounce the Doctrine of <hi>Grotius,</hi> That Colonies owe an Obſer<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>vance to their Mother Country, but not an Obedience. It is Obedience as well as Obſervance, that we owe eternally to <hi>Eng<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>land;</hi> and though our dear Mother prove never ſo unkind, we cannot throw off our Affection and Duty to her. We had ra<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ther continue our Subjection to <hi>England,</hi> in the ſad Condition we are in; then be under any others in the World, with the greateſt Eaſe and Plenty. No Advantages can tempt us to heark<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>en to any ſuch thing: nor can move in the leaſt our ſtedfaſt Loyalty. in this matter we ſhall ſtop our Ears, even to the wi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſeſt Charmers. Nor ſhall we only not affect ſuch a Change, but we ſhall likewiſe oppoſe it to the uttermoſt of our power. Up<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>on ſuch an occaſion, we ſhall cheerfully expoſe our ſelves to hardſhips and dangers of every kind; and fight for our Drudgery and Beggery, as freely as others do for their Liberties and For<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tunes. Nay though it were repreſented to us, that our ſetting up for our ſelves were never ſo feaſible and beneficial; yet we ſhould loathe that Liberty, that would rob us of our dependence upon our dear native Country.</p>
            <pb n="16" facs="tcp:104458:10"/>
            <p>WE, and thoſe under whom we claim, have (without any Aſſiſtance from the Publick) ſettled theſe Plantations, with very great Expence and Charge, with infinite Labour, with Ha<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>zards innumerable. and with Hardſhips that cannot be expreſt. And now when we thought to have had ſome fruit of our Indu<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſtry, we find our ſelves moſt miſerably diſappointed. Our Mea<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſures are broken, and our Hopes are confounded, and our For<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tunes are at once ruined, by Preſſures and Taxes which we are not able to bear. Is all our Care and Pains come to this? and is this the End and Upſhot of all our Adventures? Have we gone ſo many hundred Leagues, and hewed out our Fortunes in another World; to have the Marrow ſuck'd out of our Bones by Taxes and Impoſitions? Had theſe things been foreſeen, it had cool'd the Courage of our moſt forward Adventurers. They would never have gone ſo far, to be made Rogues of by thoſe that ſtaid at home. They would have thought it more adviſa<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ble to ſit by the Fire ſide, and to ſleep in a whole Skin.</p>
            <p>Many of us have our Eſtates by purchaſe: and we thought we had purchaſed Eſtates, but now they prove juſt nothing. though moſt commonly we laid out upon them all we had, and all that we could borrow.</p>
            <p>Some of the Plantations, 'tis true, came to <hi>England</hi> by Con<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>queſt. But muſt the Conquerors themſelves be look't upon as a conquered People? It were very ſtrange, if thoſe that bring Countries under the Dominion of <hi>England,</hi> and maintain the poſſeſſion, ſhould by ſo doing loſe their own <hi>Engliſh</hi> Liberties.</p>
            <p>In former daies we were under the pleaſing ſound of Privi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ledges and Immunities. of which a free Trade was one. though we counted That, a Right and not a Priviledge. But without ſuch Encouragements, the Plantations had been ſtill wild Woods. Now thoſe things are vaniſht and forgotten: and we hear of no<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>thing but Taxes and Burdens. All the Care now is, to pare us cloſe, and keep us low. We dread to be mention'd in an Act of Parliament; becauſe it is alwaies to do us Miſchief.</p>
            <p>We hear that the People of <hi>Carolina</hi> go upon the making of Silk: which ſurely is one of the beſt Commodities in the World. and the Deſign ſeems very hopeful. But it were but fair to let them know before hand, That when they have brought their matters to any perfection, there will be ways found to leave
<pb n="17" facs="tcp:104458:10"/>them not worth a Groat; and to make them miſerable Drudges and Beggers, even as We are. It will then be time for them, to be improved to the advantage of <hi>England.</hi>
            </p>
            <p>The Improvement of the Plantations to the advantage of <hi>Eng<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>land</hi> ſounds ſo bravely, and ſeems to the Projectors a thing ſo plauſible; that they would have it believed to be their chief Aim and End, in all that they do againſt us. And then they think they talk very wiſely, when they talk of Improving the Planta<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tions to the advantage of <hi>England.</hi> Juſt as a Landlord would improve his Mannor, by racking his Lands to the utmoſt Rent. or as the Maſters of Slaves, improve and contrive their Labour to their own beſt advantage. But it is our miſery and ruin to be thus improved. And ſo it would be to the Counties of Wales, or any <hi>Engliſh</hi> Counties, to be improved to the advantage of the reſt.</p>
            <p>THE CERTAIN Charges of a Sugar work are ſo great, and the Caſualties ſo many; that it were no eaſy matter to bear up againſt them, though there were no other Preſſure. The ve<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ry hanging of our Coppers and Stills is a great conſtant Charge. It comes often to be done; and every one of them that is new hang'd, doth coſt us one way or other at leaſt three pound. Be<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſide, they are perpetually burning out and ſpoyling: and the buying of new ones comes to a great deal of Money.</p>
            <p>We muſt have yearly ſome hundred pairs of Sugar-Pots and Jarrs. Every hundred pair doth coſt neer ten pound; and we muſt fetch them ſeveral Miles upon <hi>Negroes</hi> Heads.</p>
            <p>The Wear of our Mills (to ſay nothing now of the Tear, which is caſual) is alſo a continual Charge to us. And if a Mill be to be new built, and made perfect in all its parts, it coſts neer five hundred pound.</p>
            <p>The Fraight of every Servant that we have from <hi>England</hi> is five pound: and their Cloths and other Neceſſaries come to lit<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tle leſs. Which Fraight and Charges the Maſters of Ships will be allowed for them, if they are brought over upon the Ships account. Their Time may not be above five years, and is com<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>monly but four.</p>
            <pb n="18" facs="tcp:104458:11"/>
            <p>We muſt have a great many Horſes, and (in <hi>Barbados</hi>) we ſcarce breed any. The Fraight of a Horſe from <hi>England</hi> (with his Hay and Water) is ten pound. and a great hazard of loſing him by the way.</p>
            <p>He that hath but a hundred <hi>Negroes,</hi> ſhould buy half a dozen every year to keep up his ſtock. And they will coſt, as it hath been noted, about twenty pound a Head.</p>
            <p>A good Over ſeer will have a hundred pound a year. Some give a great deal more. There are others alſo that muſt have great Salaries, and we cannot be without them.</p>
            <p>The ramaſſing the vaſt quantities of Dung we muſt uſe, the carrying it to the Field, and diſpoſing it there; is a mighty Labour, which in effect is Charge. An Acre of ground well dreſs'd, will take thirty load of Dung: and he that hath two Wind mills, muſt plant yearly neer a hundred Acres.</p>
            <p>We carry Mould and Cane-Traſh, or any thing that is pro<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>per, into our Cattle Pens, and into our Still-Ponds; to turn all into Dung. We take all ways and means for the raiſing of Dung; and we rake and ſcrape Dung out of every Corner. Some ſave the Urine of their People (both Whites and Blacks) to increaſe and enrich their Dung.</p>
            <p>We make high and ſtrong Walls or VVears to ſtop the Mould that waſhes from our Grounds: which we carry back in Carts or upon <hi>Negroes</hi> heads. Our <hi>Negrees</hi> work at it like Ants or Bees.</p>
            <p>Moreover the Charge of our <hi>Militia</hi> is exceeding great upon us. In <hi>Barbados,</hi> every twenty Acres muſt find a Footman, and every forty Acres a Horſeman. So that an Eſtate of five hun<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dred Acres ſends five Horſemen and fifteen Foot. which is more then is done here by the greateſt Peer in <hi>England.</hi> Perhaps this may ſeem incredible; but it is moſt true. for our Law is expreſly ſo, and it is ſtrictly executed. Alſo every one that keeps a Horſe, muſt ſerve on Horſeback; and every other Houſekeeper muſt ſerve on foot. Otherwiſe our <hi>Militia</hi> could not riſe (as it doth) to ſix Regiments of Foot and two Regiments of Horſe; beſide a Life-Guard for the Governour, of a hundred Gentlemen. and all this, in a Place no bigger then the Iſle of <hi>Wight.</hi> It muſt be added, that the other Plantations have as great a Share of this
<pb n="19" facs="tcp:104458:11"/>Burden: that is to ſay, in proportion to the value of their Eſtates though not to the Quantity of their Land. And we are forced to be thus upon our Guard, and to ſtrain our ſelves in this man<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ner; our All lying at ſtake, our Enemies being near us, and our Friends (if we have any) being far from us. But we in <hi>Barbados</hi> have a Charge extraordinary in this Matter. for all that ſerve in Our <hi>Militia</hi> muſt appear in Red Coats. This was put upon us by <hi>Dutton</hi> when he was Governour. He would have it; and made us inſert it in our Act of <hi>Militia.</hi> And it hath driven many a poor Houſe keeper from off the I ſland.</p>
            <p>IF the conſtant Charge of a Plantation is terrible, the Caſual<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ties do not come behind. For let a Planter be never ſo careful, he muſt by open to many and various Accidents: and like <hi>Job</hi>'s Meſſengers, one in the neck of another, his People will bring him Tidings of continual Loſſes and Diſaſters.</p>
            <p>We cannot ſay that Horſes and Cattle are much more caſual with us, then they are in other places. only our loſs is the great<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>er, in regard they coſt us much dearer. But our Canes, on which we rely and which are our Eſtate, are too often burnt down before our faces when they are ready to cut. They are then like Tinder: and if a Fire get amongſt them, a whole Field of them is conſumed in a few Minutes. Alſo our Boyling-hou<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſes and Still-houſes are very ſubject to Fire.</p>
            <p>Sometimes we ſuffer by extreme Droughts, and ſometimes by continual violent Rains. And a ſudden Guſt will tear or maim our Windmills. But if a <hi>Hurricane</hi> come, it makes a deſolation: and puts us to begin the World anew. The damage it does the Planter is ſometimes ſo great, that the pro<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fit of divers years muſt go to repair it.</p>
            <p>Our Negroes, which coſt us ſo dear, are alſo extremely caſual. When a man hath bought a parcel of the beſt and ableſt he can get for money; let him take all the care he can, he ſhall loſe a full third part of them, before they ever come to do him ſervice. When they are ſeaſon'd, and uſed to the Country, they ſtand much better. but to how many Miſchances are they ſtill ſubject? If a Stiller ſlip into a Rum-Ciſtern, it is ſudden death: for it ſtiſles in a moment. If a Mill-feeder be catch't by the finger, his whole body is drawn in, and he is
<pb n="20" facs="tcp:104458:12"/>ſqueez'd to pieces. If a Boyler get any part into the ſcalding Sugar, it ſticks like Glew, or Birdlime, and 'tis hard to ſave either Limb or Life. They will quarrell, and kill one another, upon ſmall occaſions: by many Accidents they are diſabled, and become a burden: they will run away, and perhaps be never ſeen more: or they will hang themſelves, no creature knows why. And ſometimes there comes a Mortality amongſt them, which ſweeps a great part of them away.</p>
            <p>When this happens, the poor Planter is in a hard condition: eſpecially if he be ſtill indebted for them. He muſt have more Negroes, or his Works muſt ſtand, and he muſt be ruin'd at once. And he cannot procure them without contracting new Debts; which perhaps he ſhall never be able to work out.</p>
            <p>Theſe are ſome of the Charges and Caſualties that attend Plantations. It would be too tedious to number them all; and they are hardly to be numbered.</p>
            <p>IF OUR <hi>Empſons</hi> and <hi>Dudleys</hi> had duly conſider'd theſe things, they would have laid aſide their inhumane Project a<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>gainſt the poor Plantations. But they conſider nothing, but how they may do moſt miſchief.</p>
            <p>Theſe are the Men that will perſwade Princes, that it is a more glorious Conqueſt to cruſh their own Subjects, then to ſubdue-an Enemy.</p>
            <p>Theſe Men ſeem to be trying Concluſions, whether they can ſo far provoke us, as to make us deſperate. And as much as in them lyes, they would make the very Name of <hi>England</hi> hatefull to us. But there is no danger. For we ſhall bear whatſoever is laid upon us, with the moſt ſubmiſſive patience; and nothing can make us forget or lay down our love, to the <hi>Engliſh</hi> Name and Nation.</p>
            <p>They would make our Great and Dear Mother, <hi>England,</hi> to be ſo cruel and unnatural, as to deſtroy and devour her own Children.</p>
            <p>They would put us in the diſmal Condition of thoſe that ſaid, being oppreſt by a hard Maſter; <hi>Subjectos nos habuit tanquam ſuos, &amp; viles ut alienos. We are commanded as Subjects, and we are cruſht as Aliens.</hi> Which Condition is the moſt diſmall and horrid, that people can be under.</p>
            <pb n="21" facs="tcp:104458:12"/>
            <p>They would uſe us like Sponges: or like Sheep. They think us fit to be ſqueezed and fleeced; as ſoon as we have got any Moiſture within us, or any Wooll upon us.</p>
            <p>Theſe <hi>Egyptian</hi> Tax maſters would bring us into the Stare of <hi>Villenage.</hi> They would make us the Publique <hi>Vilieins.</hi> They would have us work and labour, to pay the Publique Taxes, as far as it will go.</p>
            <p>They would make meer <hi>Gibeonites</hi> of us: hewers of Wood, and drawers of Water. And tho theſe things muſt inevitably bring us to deſolation and deſtruction, what do the Projectors care?</p>
            <p>But although we are deſigned by the Projectors to be made perfect <hi>Villeins,</hi> yet they ſhould remember, that even <hi>Villeins</hi> muſt not be miſuſed too much. We are told out of old Law Books, that <hi>'tis Waſt for the Tenant to miſentreat the Villeins of the Mannor, ſo that they depart from the Mannor, and depart from their tenures.</hi> And in another place; <hi>Deſtruction of Villeins by tallage is adjudged Waſt.</hi> In which Caſes the Writ ſays; <hi>Quod fecit Vaſtum, deſtructionem, &amp; exilium.</hi> Surely in our Caſe, there is a plain deſtruction by Tallage.</p>
            <p>The names of old <hi>Empſon</hi> and <hi>Dudley</hi> are infamous and odi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ous to this day. And they were hang'd for their Villianies Yet they ruin'd men but ſingly, and one by one. How much higher Gibbets, and how much greater deteſtation, do theſe men deſerve, that have deſtroyed whole Countreys?</p>
            <p>A Quack pretending great Skill, makes a Woman give her Child Arſenick: he facing her down, that Arſenick is not poy<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſon. the Child is kill'd, and the Quack is hang'd. Even ſo our dear Mother hath ſeen a Cup of deadly Poyſon, given to her Children the Plantations: theſe men (who would be thought great Quacks in Trade) giving the higheſt aſſurances that the Drench ſhould do no harm: by which means the Plantations are murder'd and deſtroyed. And ſhall not theſe Men be hang'd? Some think they deſerve it better, then all that have been hang'd at Tyburn this twice ſeven years.</p>
            <p>THE Projectors might think, in the Naughtineſs of their hearts, that many would favour this Project againſt us, for their
<pb n="22" facs="tcp:104458:13"/>owne Eaſe: and would be willing, or at leaſt content, to have the Plantations bear the whole Burden. Not caring how heavy the burden lay upon others, ſo they could ſhift it off from themſelves. But this is a thing of ſo great baſeneſs, that we are very confident, it cannot enter into the heart of any Engliſh man, the Projectors themſelves excepted. At leaſt there is no Engliſh Parliament but will put it far from them. They know that they are entruſted to do equal and righteous Things. They know that the raiſing of Money is one of the moſt important things in a State. If it be done equally, though the burden be heavy, yet it is born with cheerfulneſs. If otherwiſe, it oc<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>caſions furious Diſcontents, and at laſt brings all to Confuſion. When a Government falls once to ſhifting and ſharking, (par<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>don the expreſſion, I hope we are not concern'd in it'); it is a great ſign that that Government will not ſtand. No Society of Men can ſtand without equal Juſtice, which is the Lady and Queen of all the Vertues. If the equal dividing the common Booties, be neceſſary to Pirates and <hi>Buccaneers;</hi> the equal di<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſtribution of publique Burdens, is much more to a State.</p>
            <p>But it is the Projectors baſe ſharking Principle to make Ine<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>quality in theſe Matters: and to get Eaſe to themſelves by laying the burden upon others. The Writer of theſe Papers heard one of them ſay (it was, after that the late Parliament had been ſo liberal: I forbear his Name, I would not put that Brand upon him): but he ſaid Vauntingly, in his drink; <hi>We have given the King ſeveral Millions of Money, and I ſhall not pay ſix pence towards it.</hi> And yet he was a great landed Man. which alſo made the ſaying the leſs become him.</p>
            <p>The <hi>Projectors</hi> chief skill is to fall upon the weakeſt, and make Them pay all. But then why do not they perſuade the <hi>Weſtern</hi> men, ſince they can out-vote the <hi>Northern,</hi> to make them pay all the Taxes, themſelves paying nothing? Or why do they not ſingle out a few Counties, which by the com<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>bining of the reſt againſt them, may be made to pay Taxes for all the reſt? The ſix <hi>Weſtern</hi> Counties (for now the Dice are turn'd againſt Them) are in value above two Millions yearly. So that a Tax of two thirds (ſuch as the Plantations now bear) would amount yearly to thirteen hundred thouſand
<pb n="23" facs="tcp:104458:13"/>pounds. And if this were kept conſtantly upon them, all the reſt of the Kingdom needed to pay nothing. But perhaps theſe things might coſt a great deal of Noiſe. They might there<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fore, to go a ſmoother way, direct their Projects againſt Widows and Orphans, and Heirs within age. If theſe were tax'd, well towards the value of their Eſtates, it would-be a great Eaſe to the reſt of the Kingdom.</p>
            <p>BUT our Maſters the <hi>Projectors</hi> think they have a great ad<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>vantage over us, in regard we have none to repreſent us in Parliament. 'Tis true, we have not: but we hope we may have them. It is no diſparagement to the Kingdome of <hi>Portugall,</hi> rather it is the only thing that looks great; that in the aſ<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſembly of their Eſtates, the Deputies of the City of <hi>Goa</hi> have their place, among their other Cities. But at preſent we have them not and what follows? Muſt we therefore be made meer Beaſts of burden? It is not long, ſince the Biſhoprick of <hi>Durham</hi> had any repreſentatives in Parliament. But we do not find, that before they had this Priviledge, they were in the leaſt over-laid with Taxes. Alſo there are now divers Counties that have but few Members in compariſon. <hi>Eſſex</hi> hath but eight: whereas <hi>Cornwall,</hi> which is of much leſs value, hath a<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>bove forty. But becauſe they have not half their proportion of Members, muſt an advantage be taken againſt them, to make them pay double their proportion of Taxes?</p>
            <p>THEY have a Saying Beyond Sea of Us Engliſh Men, that we will not let others live by us. The Saying is falſe: but if it were never ſo true, ſure it would not hold among our ſelves, but is only in relation to Strangers. To be cruel to and among our ſelves, would be a Cruelty without Example. Even Wolves and Bears ſpare their own Kind; nor is there to be found ſo fell a Monſter in Nature, as to deny his Bro<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ther Monſters their Means of living. What do the Projectors take us to be? Are we not of your own number? are we not Engliſh Men? Some of us pretend to have as good <hi>Engliſh</hi> Bloud in our Veins, as ſome of thoſe that we left behind us. How
<pb n="24" facs="tcp:104458:14"/>came we to loſe our Countrey, and the Priviledges of it? Why will you caſt us out?</p>
            <p>SUPPOSE a Quantity of Land were gain'd here out of the Sea, by private Adventurers, as bigg as two or three Counties. (Never ſay that the thing is impoſſible; for we may ſuppoſe any thing.) Suppoſe alſo, that people went by degrees from all parts of <hi>England,</hi> to inhabit and cultivate this New Coun<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>try. Would you now look upon theſe people as Forrainers and Aliens? Would you grudge at their Thriving and Proſpe<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rity, and ply them with all the methods of Squeezing and Flee<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cing? Would you forbid them all forrain Trade; and ſo bur<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>den their Trade to <hi>England,</hi> that their Eſtates ſhould become worth nothing? Would you make them pay the full value of their Lands in Taxes and Impoſitions? It cannot be thought that you would do theſe things. rather you would eſteem the Country a part of <hi>England,</hi> and cheriſh the People as <hi>Eng<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>liſh</hi> Men. And why may not the Plantations expect the like Kindneſs and Favour? If the thing be duly weighed, They alſo are meer Additions and Acceſſions to <hi>England,</hi> and Enlargements of it. And our caſe is the very ſame with the caſe ſuppoſed. Only herein lies the difference, that there is a diſtance and ſpace between <hi>England</hi> and the Plantations. So that we muſt loſe our Country upon the account of Space. a thing little more then imaginary: a thing next neighbour to nothing.</p>
            <p>The Citizens of <hi>Rome,</hi> though they lived in the remoteſt Parts of the World then known, were ſtill <hi>Roman</hi> Citizens to all Intents. But we poor Citizens of <hi>England,</hi> as ſoon as our backs are turn'd, and we are gone a ſpit and a ſtride; are preſently reputed Aliens, and uſed accordingly.</p>
            <p>IT is a great wonder that theſe Projectors never took <hi>Ireland</hi> to task. They might there have had a large Field for their ſqueezing and fleecing Projects. And they might have found out wayes, to skim the Cream of all the Eſtates in <hi>Ireland.</hi> But what is it they could have done in this Affair? the an<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſwer is, that they might have thought of ſeveral good things. In the firſt place, Nothing to be brought to <hi>Ireland,</hi> or carried
<pb n="25" facs="tcp:104458:14"/>thence, but in Engliſh Ships, navigated by Engliſh Men. The next thing had been, to conſider, what things thoſe People had moſt occaſion for: and to put thoſe Things under a ſe<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>vere Monopoly. which alſo muſt be in the Conduct and Man<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>agement of a Company here in <hi>England.</hi> Then care ſhould be taken, that what ever is carried out of <hi>Ireland,</hi> be brought directly to <hi>England</hi> and to no place elſe: and what ever that Country wants, be had only from <hi>England.</hi> By which means, <hi>England</hi> would be the Staple, of all the Commodities import<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ed thither, or exported thence. There is alſo another thing, which is by no means to be forgotten: and that is, That the Commodities they ſend into <hi>England</hi> may be under ſuch Im<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>poſitions, as may drink up the whole Profit.</p>
            <p>Theſe are ſome of the VVaies for Improving <hi>Ireland</hi> to the advantage of <hi>England.</hi> Nor can any thing hinder their Exe<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cution; in regard thoſe People are in our power, as well as the Plantations, and ſubject to the Laws of <hi>England</hi> when we pleaſe to name them. But you will ſay; Theſe things make up ſuch a Devilliſh Oppreſſion, as is not to be endured. Tru<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ly it muſt be confeſst, that the things may ſeem ſomething hard. But yet there is no Oppreſſion in the caſe. For all theſe things, and divers more of the like nature, do the Plantations ly under.</p>
            <p>The Projectors think they have been very merciful to us, in that the new Duties are to continue but eight years. They might tell a Man as well, that in pity and tenderneſs to him, they will hold his head under water but half an hour, or keep him but a Week without Victuals: that is, long enough to deſtroy him. For the Plantations will be certainly ruin'd with<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>in that time, if theſe Burdens ly upon them: ſome few per<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>haps excepted, who had Money beforehand, or have Eſtates in <hi>England.</hi> And theſe alſo muſt be involved in the general Ruine.</p>
            <p>HITHERTO WE have given ſome account of our de<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>plorable Condition. But to afflict us yet more, we are told that we deſerve no better uſage, in reſpect of the great
<pb n="26" facs="tcp:104458:15"/>hurt and damage we do to <hi>England:</hi> as all new Colonies do. But then it had been more prudent, and likewiſe more juſt and merciful, rather to prevent the ſettling of the Plantations, then to ruine them now they are ſettled. The leaſt ſignification that they were not pleaſing, would have kept people at home. People would never have ventured their Eſtates and Lives, and undergone ſuch Labours; to get the ill will of thoſe, whoſe Favour they valued. Had this been the opinion alwaies con<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cerning Colonies, it might paſs for a Miſtake in Judgment. But when We, who had all encouragement at firſt, ſhall as ſoon as we have got ſomething, be accounted pernicious to our Coun<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>try; we have reaſon to doubt, that this is only a pretence to oppreſs us, and not a real belief or ſentiment.</p>
            <p>If a new Country ſhould now offer, no queſtion but free leave would be given to make a Settlement, and all due En<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>couragements granted. We muſt not ſay that the People in this caſe would be decoyed and trapann'd and chous'd and chea<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ted; theſe are not fit words to be here uſed. but they would find, that they had miſerably deceived themſelves. For by that time they were warm in their Houſes, and had got things a<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>bout them; the Projectors would be upon their bones: and theſe new Favourites would be eſteemed pernicious, and uſed accordingly, as well as the reſt of the Plantations.</p>
            <p>BUT WE are very ſure, that this Opinion concerning us (if any be really of it) is a great Miſtake: and that the Plantations are not only not pernicious; but highly beneficial and of vaſt advantage to <hi>England.</hi>
            </p>
            <p>We by our Labour, Hazards, and Induſtry, have enlarged the <hi>Engliſh</hi> Trade and Empire. the <hi>Engliſh</hi> Empire in <hi>America,</hi> what ever we think of it our ſelves, is by others eſteemed greatly conſiderable.</p>
            <p>We employ ſeven or eight hundred <hi>Engliſh</hi> Ships in a ſafe and healthy Navigation. They find leſs danger in a Voyage to our Parts, then in a Voyage to <hi>Newcaſtle.</hi> And as the Ships come ſafe, ſo the Men come ſound. Whereas of thoſe that go
<pb n="27" facs="tcp:104458:15"/>to the <hi>Eaſt-Indies,</hi> half the Ships Company (take one Ship with another) periſh in the Voyage.</p>
            <p>It did the Seamens hearts good, to think of a Plantation Voyage: where they might be merry amongſt their Friends and Countrymen, and where they were ſure of the kindeſt Recep<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tion. While we had it, we thought nothing too good for them. But now their beloved Navigation is gone. For by deſtroy<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing the Plantations, it could not be, but that the Navigation to them muſt be deſtroyed likewiſe: or at leaſt made good for nothing. Which, to them, is the ſame thing as deſtroying. We are ſo pinched our ſelves by the Impoſitions, that we are forced to pinch all thoſe, with whom we are concern'd. And our Trade is become ſo hard and ſo bare a paſture, that it ſtarves every thing that relates to it. And in particular, we cannot now afford the Seamen, that liberal Fraight which we did for<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>merly. We would willingly do reaſon to our good Friends the Seamen, and give them a fair and full price for the tranſporta<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tion of our Goods; but we are not able.</p>
            <p>The Seamen did well foreſee, that they ſhould feel the ill conſequence of our new Burdens. And we have good Aſſurance, that while the thing was brewing, they had thoughts of ma<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>king humble and earneſt Addreſſes to keep them off. But the ſwiftneſs of the Projectors motion prevented their deſign.</p>
            <p>And what followed upon the laying the new Taxes? Tru<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ly ſuch a ſlight of the <hi>Engliſh</hi> Seamen in the late Reign, as never was known. They plainly deſerted the <hi>Engliſh</hi> Service. Of which there was no cauſe ſo viſible, as the ſpoiling that Navigation which was moſt dear to them. So that it plainly appears, that by the Sufferings of the Plantations, the Naviga<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tion doth highly ſuffer; whereas while they are permitted to be in a tolerable Condition, they are a great advance to the Navigation of <hi>England.</hi>
            </p>
            <p>LET us now conſider the further advantages of Trade. though the building, repairing, fitting and furniſhing ſo many Ships, and the finding Cloths and Victuals for the Seamen, is a conſiderable Trade of it ſelf. But moreover, there is hardly
<pb n="28" facs="tcp:104458:16"/>a Ship comes to us, but what is half loaden at leaſt (many of them are deep loaden) with <hi>Engliſh</hi> Commodities.</p>
            <p>Several Scores of Thouſands are employed in <hi>England,</hi> in fur<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>niſhing the Plantations with all ſorts of Neceſſaries. and theſe muſt be ſupplied the while with Cloths and Victuals, which employs great numbers likewiſe. All which are paid, out of Our Induſtry and Labour.</p>
            <p>We have yearly from <hi>England</hi> an infinite Quantity of Iron VVares ready wrought. Thouſands of Dozens of Howes, and great numbers of Bills to cut our Canes. many Barrels of Nails; many Sets of Smiths, Carpenters, and Coopers Tools; all our Locks and Hinges; with Swords, Piſtols, Carbines, Muskets, and Fowling Pieces.</p>
            <p>VVe have alſo from <hi>England</hi> all ſorts of Tin-ware, Earthen<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ware, and VVooden-ware: and all our Braſs and Pewter. And many a Serne of Sope, many a Quoyle of Rope, and of Lead many a Fodder, do the Plantations take from <hi>England.</hi>
            </p>
            <p>Even <hi>Engliſh</hi> Cloth is much worn amongſt us; but we have of Stuffs far greater Quantities. From <hi>England</hi> come all the Hats we weare; and of Shoos, thouſands of Dozens yearly. The white Broad cloth that we uſe for Strainers, comes alſo to a great deal of Money. Our very <hi>Negro</hi> Caps, of Woolen-yarn knit, (of which alſo we have yearly thouſands of Dozens) may paſs for a Manufacture.</p>
            <p>How many Spinners, Knitters, and Weavers are kept at work here in <hi>England,</hi> to make all the Stockings we wear? Woollen Stockings for the ordinary People, Silk Stockings when we could go to the price, Worſted Stockings in abundance, and Thread Stockings without number.</p>
            <p>As we have our Horſes from <hi>England;</hi> So all our Saddles and Bridles come from <hi>England</hi> likewiſe. which we deſire ſhould be good ones, and are not ſparing in the price.</p>
            <p>The Bread we eat, is of <hi>Engliſh</hi> Flower: we take great Quan<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tities of <hi>Engliſh</hi> Beer, and of <hi>Engliſh</hi> Cheeſe and Butter: we ſit by the light of <hi>Engliſh</hi> Candles; and the Wine we drink, is bought for the moſt part with <hi>Engliſh</hi> Commodities. Ships bound for the Plantations touch at <hi>Madera,</hi> and there ſell their Goods, and inveſt the Produce in Wines.</p>
            <pb n="29" facs="tcp:104458:16"/>
            <p>Moreover we take yearly thouſands of Barrels of <hi>Iriſh</hi> Beef: with the price whereof thoſe people pay their Rents, to their Landlords that live and ſpend their Eſtates in <hi>England.</hi>
            </p>
            <p>'TIS ſtrange we ſhould be thought to diminiſh the People of <hi>England,</hi> when we do ſo much increaſe the Employments. Where there are Employments, there will be People: you can<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>not keep them out, nor drive them away, with Pitchforks. On the other ſide, where the Employments faile or are want<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing, the People will be gone. they will never ſtay there to ſtarve, or to eat up one another. Great numbers of <hi>French</hi> Proteſtants that came lately to <hi>England,</hi> left us again upon this account. It was their Saying; We have been received with great Kindneſs and Charity, but here is no Imployment.</p>
            <p>However it is charged upon the Plantations (and we can be charged with nothing elſe), that they take People from <hi>England.</hi> But doth not <hi>Ireland</hi> do the ſame? It may be truly ſaid, that if the <hi>American</hi> Colonies have taken thouſands, <hi>Ireland</hi> hath taken ten thouſands. Yet we cannot find, that people were ever ſtopp'd from going thither, or that ever it was thought an Inconvenience. You will ſay the Caſes are different: in regard the <hi>Plantations</hi> are remote; whereas <hi>Ireland</hi> is neer at hand. and our people that are in <hi>Ireland</hi> can give us ready Aſſiſtance. In anſwer hereuuto it is confeſs'd, that where Co<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lonies are neer, the Power is more united. But it muſt be confeſs'd likewiſe, that where the Colonies are remote, the Power is farther extended. So that Theſe may be as uſeful one way, as Thoſe are another way. It concerns a Generall to have his Army united. but may he not detach part of it, to poſſeſs a Poſt at ſome diſtance, though it be of never ſo great advantage? It is plainly an advantage, to have a Command and Influence upon remote Parts of the World. Moreover the remote Colonies of <hi>America</hi> are much more advantageous to <hi>England</hi> in point of Trade, then is this neer one of <hi>Ireland.</hi> For Ireland producing the ſame things, takes little from us, and alſo ſpoiles our Markets in other places. Nor doth it furniſh us with any thing, which before we bought of Forrai<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ners. But the <hi>American</hi> Plantations do both take off from <hi>Eng<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>land</hi>
               <pb n="30" facs="tcp:104458:17"/>abundance of Commodities; and do likewiſe furniſh <hi>England</hi> with divers Commodities of value, which formerly were im<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ported from forrain Parts. which things are now become our owne: and are made Native. For you muſt know, and may pleaſe to conſider, That the Sugar we make in the <hi>American Plantations</hi> (to inſtance only in that) is as much a native <hi>Eng<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>liſh</hi> Commodity, as if it were made and produced in <hi>England.</hi>
            </p>
            <p>But ſtill you will ſay, that we draw People from <hi>England.</hi> We confeſs we do, as a Man draws Water from a good Well. Who the more he draws in reaſon, the more he may: the Well being continually ſupplied. <hi>Anglia puteus inexhauſtus,</hi> ſaid a Pope of old in another ſenſe, that is, in matter of Mo<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ney. But in matter of People it is likewiſe true; That <hi>Eng<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>land</hi> is a Well or Spring inexhauſted, which hath never the leſs Water in it, for having ſome drawn from it.</p>
            <p>You will ſay yet further, that the Plantations diſ-people <hi>England.</hi> But this we utterly deny. Why may not you ſay as well, that the <hi>Roman</hi> Colonies diſpeopled <hi>Rome?</hi> which yet was never pretended or imagined. That wiſe and glorious State, when ever there was a convenience of ſettling a Colony, thought fit to ſend out thouſands of people at a time, at the Publick Charge. And wiſe Men are of opinion, That as the <hi>Roman</hi> Empire was the greateſt that the World hath yet ſeen; ſo it chiefly owed its Grandeur to its free emiſſion of Colonies.</p>
            <p>And whereas the Kingdoms of <hi>Spain</hi> may ſeem diſpeopled and exhauſted by their <hi>American</hi> Colonies; if the thing be well examin'd, their Sloth and not their Colonies hath been the true Cauſe. To which may be added the Rigour of their Go<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>vernment, and their many Arts and Waies of deſtoying Trade.</p>
            <p>But what will you ſay to the <hi>Dutch?</hi> for They, we know, have Colonies in the <hi>Eaſt-Indies.</hi> Do theſe exhauſt and depo<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>pulate <hi>Holland,</hi> or at leaſt are they a Burden and an Inconve<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nience? The <hi>Dutch</hi> themſelves are ſo far from thinking ſo, that they juſtly eſteem them the chief and main foundation of their Wealth and Trade. Their <hi>Eaſt-Indy</hi> Trade depends upon their <hi>Eaſt-Indy</hi> Colonies; and their whole State in effect, that is, the Greatneſs and Glory of it, depends upon their <hi>Eaſt-Indy</hi>
               <pb n="31" facs="tcp:104458:17"/>Trade. Moreover as their Wealth and Trade increaſes, their People increaſe likewiſe.</p>
            <p>They have alſo ſome Places in the <hi>Weſt-Indies:</hi> which they prize not a little. How do they cheriſh <hi>Suranam,</hi> though it be one of the baſeſt Countries in the World? And their Iſland of <hi>Quaracoa</hi> (<hi>Cariſaw</hi> we pronounce it) they are as tender of, as any man can be of the apple of his Eye. Alſo their repeat<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ed Endeavours to ſettle <hi>Tabago</hi> do ſufficiently evince, that they would very willingly ſpare ſome of their People, to increaſe their ſhare in the Sugar Trade. But for a further proof of their Sentiment in theſe Matters; we may remember, that in the heat of their laſt War with <hi>France,</hi> they ſent their Admiral <hi>De Ruyter</hi> with a great Force, to attempt the <hi>French</hi> Sugar Iſlands in <hi>America.</hi> which they would not have done, had they not thought them highly valuable. But the <hi>French</hi> King was as mindful to keep his Iſlands, as they were to get them: and he took ſuch order and had ſuch Force to defend them, as ren<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>der'd the <hi>Dutch</hi> Attempts ineffectual. Thus the <hi>French</hi> and <hi>Dutch,</hi> while all lay at ſtake at home, were contending in the <hi>Weſt-Indies</hi> for Plantations; which our Politicians count worth no<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>thing, or worſe then nothing. You'll ſay, this ſame French Court, and theſe Dutch States, are meer ignorant Novices, and do not know the World. Perhaps not ſo well as our Politicians: But however ſomething they know.</p>
            <p>Many have obſerved that <hi>France</hi> is much diſpeopled by Tyran<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ny and Oppreſſion. But that their Plantations have in the leaſt diſpeopled it, was never yet ſaid nor thought. And That King ſets ſuch a value upon his Plantations, and is ſo far from think<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing his People loſt that are in his Plantations; that he payes a good part of the Fraight, of all thoſe that will go to them to ſettle: giving them all fair Encouragements beſides.</p>
            <p>If Colonies be ſo pernicious to their Mother Country, it was a great happineſs to <hi>Portugall,</hi> that the <hi>Dutch</hi> ſtripp'd them of their <hi>Eaſt-India</hi> Colonies. And ſurely they feel the difference: but it is much for the worſe. <hi>Lisbon</hi> is not that <hi>Lisbon</hi> now, which it was in thoſe days. And did not the recovery of <hi>Braſile</hi> (though that Trade be now low) in ſome meaſure ſup<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>port them, with the help of <hi>Madera,</hi> the <hi>Weſtern Iſlands,</hi> and
<pb n="32" facs="tcp:104458:18"/>ſome other Colonies; <hi>Portugall</hi> would be one of the pooreſt places upon Earth.</p>
            <p>BUT ſtill you perſiſt in the opinion, that the Plantations do more hurt then good, and are pernicious to <hi>England.</hi> Truly if it be ſo, it were your beſt way to ſhake them off, and cleerly to rid your hands of them. And you muſt not be averſe to this motion. For if you cry out that the Plantations do hurt, and yet are not willing to part with them, it cannot be thought that you are in earneſt. You will ſay, this ſhould have been done ſooner. But if 'tis fit to be done, 'tis better done late then not at all. Have the Plantations robbed you of your People already? Let them rob you no more. A man will ſtop a leake in his Veſſell, though ſome be run out.</p>
            <p>We of the Plantations cannot hear the mention of being caſt off by <hi>England,</hi> without regrett. Nevertheleſs if it muſt be ſo, we ſhall compoſe our Minds to bear it. and like Children truly dutifull, we ſhall be content to part with our deareſt Mo<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ther, rather than be a burden to her, But though we muſt part with our Country, yet we would not willingly part with our King: and therefore, if you pleaſe, let us be made over to <hi>Scotland.</hi> We are confident that Scotland would be well pleaſed to ſupply us with People, to have the ſweet Trade in Exchange. And we ſhould agree well with them: for we know by Experience that they are honeſt Men and good Planters. They would now be as buſy as Bees all <hi>Scotland</hi> over, work<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing merrily for the Plantations. And <hi>England</hi> the while might keep her People at home: to pick ſtrawes, or for ſome ſuch other good work. though ſome of them, 'tis doubt, would make the Highway their way of Living. And now <hi>Scotland</hi> would be the Market for Sugar: where our Friends of <hi>England</hi> would be welcome with their Money. We ſhould be glad to meet them there, and ſhould uſe them well for old acquaintance. But what would be the Effect of theſe things? The Effect would be; that in a very few years, the value of Lands in <hi>England</hi> would fall a fourth part, if not a third: and the Land in <hi>Scotland</hi> would be more than doubled. It were therefore better to acknow<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ledge,
<pb n="33" facs="tcp:104458:18"/>according to truth, that the Plantations are greatly be<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>neficial; and to keep the Plantations.</p>
            <p>There is one main advantage by the Plantations which hath not been ſufficiently explained: and that is, that we have now di<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>vers good Commodities of our own, which before we had not. which doth very much conduce to the enriching of <hi>England.</hi> For it is agreed by all that pretend to underſtand Trade, that a Country doth then grow rich, and then only, when the Com<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>modities exported out of it are more in value then thoſe that are imported into it. This proportion between the <hi>Importation</hi> and the <hi>Exportation</hi> is called the <hi>Balance of Trade.</hi> and there is no way in the World for a Country to grow rich by Trade, but by ſetting this Balance right, and by ſending out more than it takes in. Some other Tricks and ſhifts there are, which make ſhew of doing great Matters: but they prove idle and frivolous, and ſignifie juſt nothing. A Country, in this reſpect, is in the ſame Condition with a private Man that lives upon his Land. If this Man ſells more than he buys, he lays up money. If he buyes more than he ſells, he muſt run in debt, or at leaſt ſpend out of the quick ſtock. And where the Bought and the Sold are equal, he hath barely brought both Ends to<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>gether.</p>
            <p>It is therefore moſt evident, that the increaſing of Native Com<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>modities brings in Riches and Money. ſince it makes the Expor<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tation greater, or at leaſt the Importation leſs. And it is as evident, that the Plantations give <hi>England</hi> a great increaſe of Native Commodities. <hi>Cotton, Ginger, Indico,</hi> and <hi>Sugar,</hi> (to omit other things) are now the Native Commodities of <hi>England.</hi> We may inſiſt a little further upon Sugar, as being the moſt conſiderable. Heretofore we had all our Sugars from <hi>Portugall:</hi> and it is computed, that they coſt us yearly about four hundred thouſand pounds. Now that great Leak is ſtopp'd: and we hardly buy any <hi>Portugall</hi> or <hi>Braſile</hi> Sugars, being plentifully ſup<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>plied by our own Plantations. But moreover; beſide what we uſe our ſelves, we export as much Sugar to other Coun<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tries, as brings us in yearly near the ſame ſumme. So that the
<pb n="34" facs="tcp:104458:19"/>Plantations, by this one Commodity, do advance near eight hundred thouſand pounds a year, (the one half in getting, the other in ſaving), to turn the ſcale of Trade to the advantage of <hi>England.</hi>
            </p>
            <p>WHY ſhould <hi>England</hi> grudge at the proſperity and wealth of the <hi>Plantations;</hi> ſince all that is Ours, She may account her own? Not only becauſe we are really a part of <hi>England</hi> (what ever we may be accounted) as it is taken largely; but alſo becauſe all comes to this Kingdom of <hi>England</hi> properly ſo cal<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>led, theſe two and fifty Shires. By a kind of <hi>Magnetick</hi> Force <hi>England</hi> draws to it all that is good in the Planrations. It is the <hi>Center</hi> to which all things tend. Nothing but <hi>England</hi> can we reliſh or fancy: our Hearts are here, where ever our Bo<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dies be. If we get a little Money, we remit it to <hi>England.</hi> They that are able, breed up their Children in <hi>England.</hi> When we are a little eaſy, we deſire to live and ſpend what we have in <hi>England.</hi> And all that we can rap and rend is brought to <hi>England.</hi> What would you have? Would you have more of a Cat than her Skin?</p>
            <p>WE have made it out, in the former parts of theſe Papers, what Multitudes of People the Plantations employ here in <hi>Eng<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>land.</hi> It is eaſily ſaid, that if there were no ſuch thing as Plantations, thoſe People might be otherwiſe employed. And ſome Men will talk of the Fiſhing Trade, and the Linnen Trade, and other projects of the like nature. But they would do well to contrive a way, how the People imployed in them may make wages. For unleſs they do that, they do nothing. There is nothing more eaſy then to find out unprofitable Em<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ployments. But thoſe that are profitable are already over<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſtock't: and people can hardly live one by another. And there<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fore the Plantations ought in reaſon to be valued, ſince they give <hi>profitable</hi> Employments to ſo many thouſands of People. whereas the Fiſhing Trade and the Linnen Trade will not turn to profit.</p>
            <pb n="35" facs="tcp:104458:19"/>
            <p>IT IS now time that we put an end to this ſad Diſcourſe. Having made it appear, that the Plantations are brought to a miſerable and ruinous Condition; and that they have not deſerved this hard Uſage, conſidering the many and great Ad<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>vantages they bring to <hi>England.</hi>
            </p>
            <p>We have laid before you ſuch a <hi>Series</hi> of Calamities, as are not eaſy to be parallell'd. And we think our patient Submiſ<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſion under them is almoſt without Example. But we muſt beg pardon of all good Men, if we cannot be in Charity with thoſe curſed Projectors, by whom our Livelyhoods (which is in ef<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fect our Lives) have been torn from us with ſo much Inhu<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>manity.</p>
            <p>But hath our dear Mother no <hi>Bowels</hi> for her Children, that are now at the laſt Gaſp, and ly ſtruggling with the pangs of Death? Will She do nothing to deliver us from the Jaws of Death? We cannot deſpair, but that ſhe will yet look upon us with an Eye of Mercy. However we deſire it may not be ill taken, that we have eaſed our Minds by recounting our Sor<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rows. Let us not be denied the common liberty and privi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ledge of Mankind, to groan when we dy. Let not our Com<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>plaints ſeem troubleſome and offenſive; but be received with Compaſſion, as the Groans of dying Men.</p>
            <trailer>FINIS.</trailer>
         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
